Partial Inventory of the Dimitri Von Mohrenschildt Papers, 1867-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
Dimitri Von Mohrenschildt Papers,
1867-1995
71071
Von Mohrenschildt, Dimitri Sergius, 1902-
11 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 envelope. 5.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, clippings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to various aspects of Russian history and Russian emigre affairs; the acquisition of Russian historical materials; and the Russian Orthodox Church in the United States. Includes letters from Sergei A. von Mohrenschildt, Russian military historian and father of D. S. Von Mohrenschildt, describing political and economic conditions in Poland under Soviet and Lithuanian occupation, 1939-1940
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1971.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Orthodox Eastern Church, Russian--United States.; Russian Review.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; Poland.; Poland--History--Occupation, 1939-1945.; Russia.; Soviet Union.; Russia--History.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; United States.
Series Description
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE OF DARTMOUTH COLLEGE LIBRARIAN, 1934-1935. (Box No. 1)
  Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent, dealing with the Dartmouth College Library's effort to establish White Russian Archives Collection
- SUBJECT FILE, 1917-1970. (Box No. 1)
  Correspondence, reports, manuscripts, clippings and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE OF DARTMOUTH COLLEGE LIBRARIAN, 1934-1935
  - Bartlett, Ralph S., 1935 (Box 1.)
  - Brasol, Boris, 1935
  - Bunyan, James, 1935
  - Chavchavadge, Paul, 1934
  - Chernikoff, Ivan Ivanovich, 1934-35
  - Chernikoff, Maria, 1935
  - de Give, Mary L., 1935
  - Lindgren, Homer D., 1934
  - Lissovoy, Jacques M., 1935
  - Marie, Grand Duchess, 1934
  - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1935
  - Swan, A. J., Mrs., 1935
- SUBJECT FILE, 1917-1970
  - Chernikoff, Ivan Ivanovich (Box 1.)
  - Dartmouth College White Russian Archives, 1934-1935
  - "Letters from Soviet Russia," describing conditions in Russia in August and September 1918 by Jacques Merpert. In French
  - Letters of S. A. Von Mohrenschildt describing political and economic conditions in Wilno, Poland, under Soviet and Lithuanian occupation, 1939 October 2, May 5, and 1940 July 8
  - Russian Orthodox Church in America. Autocephaly, 1970